<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bite Sized Python Tips</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/beta/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/beta/feeds/helptutorialwelcome.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://yasoob.github.io/beta/</id><updated>2014-01-04T04:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Future Plans and logit-bin</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/beta/future-plans-and-logit-bin" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-04T04:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/beta,2014-01-04:future-plans-and-logit-bin</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh hi there guys. Its been really a long time since I wrote my last post. Don't think that I forgot about you guys. I was just a hell lot busy in recent days. Firstly my own exams. But I am happy to tell you guys that I was really successful in them. Secondly I had a competition coming up so I remained a lot busy. So what about the next post. The next post which is currently in draft form is "writing cleanup script in python". The next post will include writing scripts that do house keeping tasks for you. I will be focusing on deleting files based on specific criteria e.g based on last modified time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also working on a website. It is a pastebin made in flask. &lt;a href="http://logit-bin.herokuapp.com"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is currently online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; but still a lot of work is to be done. You might be wondering what features does my pastebin provide. So here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anonymous pasting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep track of your pastes and comments by signing up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;commenting system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to paste reply pastes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diff between the original and reply paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only paste creator can delete a particular paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those were some of the plus points of my pastebin. I would really like to gather some feedback regarding that website. Please make sure that you take a look and share your thoughts in the comments. &lt;strong&gt;I would be making the pastebin Open Source on Github once I clean up the code a little bit.&lt;/strong&gt; I would be waiting for your feedback. Lastly I would like to wholeheartedly thank all those who take out some time and provide me with some feedback regarding my pastebin so that I can improve on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get more regular updates consider following me on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/yasoobkhalid"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; The paste bin is available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/yasoob/logit-bin"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="deleting files with python"></category><category term="deleting python"></category><category term="future plans"></category><category term="logit-bin"></category><category term="writing clean up script in python"></category></entry></feed>